Guide to the Search for Common Ground records, 1980s - 2000s
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Search for Common Ground records
1980s-2000s
C0278
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
5.0 linear feet (15 boxes)
111 videotape cassettes that document the work of Search for Common Ground.
Search for Common Ground.
Access Restrictions
SCRC does not have the capability to view betacam videocassettes. These items may require digitization in order to be viewed.
Acquisition Information
Donated by John Marks in 2015.
Historical Information
Search for Common Ground is an international non-profit organization with the aim of promoting and implementing peaceful, non-adversarial conflict resolutions. The organization was founded in 1982 by John Marks, and is currently headquartered in Washington, D.C. and Brussels, Belgium. The organization also operates media production through Common Ground Productions.
Scope and Content
111 videotape cassettes that document the work of Search for Common Ground, mostly masters in betacam format of programs the organization made in past years - "Shape of the Future" from Israel-Palestine, "Nashe Maalo" from Macedonia, Africa: Search for Common Ground, pan-African, and the "Search for Common Ground " series for US public television.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in order of size, the original order in which it was received by the donor, and numerically within the original order, respectively. Note: When numbers were not provided for individual tapes, they were placed after numbered tapes from the boxes/in the order they were received in.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds several other collection on conflict resolution, including the, the, and the
Index Terms
Persons:
Marks, John
Geographical Names:
Africa.; Angola.; Israel.; Macedonia.; Palestine.; South Africa.
Subjects:
Conflict management.; Israel/Palestine.; Portuguese.; Television and children.; Television--United States.
Contents List
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 1 "Thokosa Video Dialogue", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1030)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 2 "Ex-Zaire/South Africa", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1031)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 3 "Rwanda/Burundi", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1032)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 4 "Mozambique/Angola", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1033)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 5 "Uganda/Liberia", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1034)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 6 "South Africa - Witches", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1035)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 7 "Western Sahara/Niassa", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1036)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 8 "Mali/Lesotho", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1037)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 9 "South Africa - T and R", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1038)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 10 "Boabab Tree/Peace Song", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1039)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 11 "Algeria", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1040)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 12 "Eretria/Kenya", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1041)
  - Africa: Search For Common Ground, Program 13 "San Soldiers", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1042)
  - Hawe Maano, Episode 1, Textless, The New Knight, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1216)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #1 The New Knight, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1217)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #2 Boys and Girls, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1218)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #3 The Other Side of the River, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1219)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #4 Granny, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1220)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #5 Tarabuka, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1221)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #6 The Cure, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1222)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #7 Secrets, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1223)
  - Cyrillic Text - Episode #8 Nerds, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1224)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 2, "Kazi Stop," "Say Stop" Ang, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1801)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 3, "Golemi I Mali," "The Small and the Big Ones" Ang, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1802)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 4, "Potragata Na Ivan," "Ivan's Quest", circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1803)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 5, "The Lie" Ang, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1805)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 6, "Karmen Si Odi" - Part 1, "Carmen is Leaving" Part 1 English, Ang, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1818)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 6, "Karmen Si Odi" - Part 2, "Carmen is Leaving" Part 2 English Ang, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1819)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 1, "Izlozbata Na Ice," "Ice's Exhibition" Ang, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1820)
  - Season One: Episode 6, "The Ragman", 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1006)
  - Season One: Episode 7, "Dime's Party", 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1007)
  - Season One: Episode 8, "The Picnic", 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1008)
  - "Music Video w/ Peace Teaser" - Nashe Maalo For Peace - Macedonian and Albanian Version, March 17, circa 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1070)
  - Nasshe Maalo, Episode #: 1 "The Building Comes To Life", January 14, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1206)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode #: 2 "Mali Has A Little Lamb", January 14, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1207)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode #: 3 "Necklace", January 14, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1208)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episdoe #: 4 "Beni's Choice", January 14, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1209)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode #: 5 "Who Stole The Rabbit", January 14, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1210)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode #: 7 "Dime's Party", January 14, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1212)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Joao Batista, circa 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1230)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "What if..." - Episode 1, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1600)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "Ivan" - Episode 2, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1601)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "Music Magic" - Episode 3, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1602)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "New Girl" - Episode 4, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1603)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "Bride" - Episode 5, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1604)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "Home" - Episode 6, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1605)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "Seeds of Love" - Episode 7 - "Sound totally out of sync", circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1606)
  - Nashe Maalo, Season 4, "Remziye's Problem" - Episode 8 - "Sound out of sync totally", circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1607)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 1: Love Story, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1642)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 2: Garbage, circa 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1643)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 3: Red Car, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1644)
  - Episode 4: True Fairy Story, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1645)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 5: My Dog, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1646)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 6: Elvis and I, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1647)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 7: Darko and Aliens, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1648)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 8: Fat, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1649)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 9: Ghost, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1650)
  - Nashe Maalo, Episode 10: Fan File, circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1651)
  - "What's the Common Ground between PAC and ANC?" Search for Common Ground, Bailey and Assoc., circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1056)
  - NTSC, "Macedonian TV Interview", October 15, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1060)
  - The Angolan Peace Song - Portuguese Master, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1092)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Bernadette Lututkuta, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1227)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Carlos e Nino, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1228)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Sara Fialho, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1229)
  - Luzes Na sombra, Jose Sampaio, NTSC, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1231)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Luisa Grillo, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1232)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Jose Chicoco, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1233)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Tadeu Tchenzo, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1234)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Ana da Costa-Conceicao Pombal, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1235)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Lourenco Mateus, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1236)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Emanuel Sapalo, circa 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1237)
  - Luzes Na Sombra, Penina Paolino, circa 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1238)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 1, LONDON CALLING - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1545)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 2, THEATER GHOST - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1546)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 3, WhO IS PETER? - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1547)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 4, STAVROS' DELIMMA - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1548)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 5, READY? SET? BUSTED! - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1549)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 6, WE CAN DO IT - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1550)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 7, SEARCHING FOR PROOF - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1551)
  - GIMME 6 - Episode 8, WHERE IS NEVER NEVER LAND? - English Subtitles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1552)
  - The Kwitny Report #221 "Search for Common Ground", circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1637)
  - The Shape of the Future - Music Video Promo, NTSC "In My Heart", circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1686)
  - Common Ground Productions, The Shape of the Future, Security and the Quest for a Normal Life, Program 4, Arabic, circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1688)
  - The Shape of the Future, Settlements, English, circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1695)
  - Shape of the Future "Settlements" Eng Dub, June 29, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 1704)
  - SFCG Organizational Video 2003, December 11, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1724)
  - Ziggy Marley's Message to the People of Burundi, circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1728)
  - Centre Lokole Presents: Le Theatre Participatif Pour La Transformation des Conflits, circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1844)
  - Shape of the Future "Refugees" Eng Dub, August 22, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 1852)
  - Radio for Peacebuilding - Africa CD - Version 1, circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder No number)
  - Radio for Peacebuilding - Africa CD - Version 3 - Two Copies, circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder No number)
  - Search for Common Ground, Gambling, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1019)
  - Searh for Common Ground, Gun Running - Bad Copy, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1020)
  - Search for Common Ground, Land, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1021)
  - Search for Common Ground, Death Penalty, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1022)
  - Peace Cafe Special, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1023)
  - Search for Common Ground, Gun Running, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1024)
  - Search for Common Ground - Toxic Waste, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1025)
  - Search for Common Ground - Death, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1026)
  - Search for Common Ground - Polygamy, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1027)
  - Search for Common Ground - Prostitution, circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1028)
  - Africa: Search for Common Ground, Program 9, South Africa, Between Confession and Prosecution: Truth and Reconciliation, circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1029)
  - Burundi Peace Song, circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1093)
  - The Angolan Peace Song, circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1514)
  - Common Ground - Uncommon Hope, circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1732)
  - Angola Peace Song - Video Clip - Master, circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder No number)
  - Search for Common Ground Organizational Video, 2003 (Box 11, Folder No number)
  - Search for Common Ground - Organizational Video - "Old Version", circa 2003 (Box 11, Folder No number)
  - Search for Common Ground - Organizational Video, circa 2003 (Box 11, Folder No number)
  - Nashe Maalo, Ep. 1 New knight, Ep. 2 Momcinja and Devjcinia - Boys and Girls, Ep. 3 The Other Side of the River, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1170)
  - Nase Maalo #5, Episode 8 "The Best of Nase Maalo" "The Best of Nase Maalo" English Ang, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1499?)
  - Nashe Maalo, Ep. 4 Granny, Baba, Ep. 5 Tarabuka, Ep. 6 The Cure, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1171)
  - Nashe Maalo, Ep. 7 Secrets, Ep. 8 Nerds, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1172)
  - Romeo and Juliet In Black and White, circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1684)
  - The Shape of the Future Part 01 NTSC, circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder No number)
  - The Shape of the Future Part 02 NTSC, circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder No number)
  - Search for Common Ground, Abortion, August 25, 31, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1175)
  - Search for Common Ground #103 "Human Rights", September 1, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1176)
  - #106 "Cuba" - Search for Common Ground Series, October 4, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1177)
  - #107 "Energy" Search for Common Ground Series, October 12, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1178)
  - Search for Common Ground - Prostitution, circa 1995 (Box 14, Folder 1179)
  - Search for Common Ground - Land, circa 1995 (Box 15, Folder 1180)
  - Search for Common Ground "Gun Control", "What's the Common Ground on Gun Control", circa 1995 (Box 15, Folder 1494)
  - ABC News Nightline "Voice of Hope", November 21, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 1667)